Look at the people around you.
看看你周围的人。
Some are passive, others more aggressive.
有的人消极被动，有的人则更为强势。
Some work best alone, others crave companionship.
有的人独自工作时表现最好，有的人则渴望有人陪伴。
We easily recognize that there is great variation among the individuals who live near us.
我们很容易认识到，住在我们附近的人个体差异很大。
Yet, when we speak of people from elsewhere, we seem to inevitably characterize them based on their country of origin.
然而，说起来自别处的人，我们似乎不可避免地会根据他们的原籍国来描述其特点。
Statistics specialists, when they speak of national averages, often make the same mistake.
统计专家在谈到全国平均水平时，常常犯同样的错误。
Newly published research shows how erroneous such overviews are.
新近发表的研究表明，这类概括有多么错误。
Three researchers analyzed decades of values-based surveys and found that only between 16% and 21% of the variation in cultural values could be explained by differences between countries.
三位研究人员分析了几十年来基于价值观的调查，发现文化价值观的差异只有16%到21%能用国家之间的差异来解释。
In other words, the vast majority of what makes us culturally distinct from one another has nothing to do with our homeland.
换句话说，让我们在文化上彼此有别的因素，绝大部分都与我们来自哪个国家毫无关系。
To determine what factors really are associated with culture, the authors combined data from 558 prior surveys that each measured one or more of Hofstede’s cultural dimensions.
为了确定哪些因素真正与文化相关，作者们合并了此前558项调查的数据，每项调查都测量了霍夫斯泰德文化维度中的一项或多项。
These are traits, such as individualism and masculinity, that describe work-related cultural values.
这些维度是个人主义、男性化之类的特征，描述的是与工作相关的文化价值观。
(They are not a measure of visible cultural traits, such as food or dress.)
（这些维度衡量的并不是食物、服饰之类看得见的文化特征。）
Though the validity of Hofstede’s dimensions has been questioned, they have the singular benefit of having been in use for decades, which allows for historical and international comparisons.
尽管霍夫斯泰德文化维度的有效性受到过质疑，但它们有一个独特的优势：已经使用了几十年，这使历史比较和国际比较成为可能。
The researchers found that both demographic factors, such as age, and environmental factors, such as long-term unemployment rates, were more correlated with cultural values than nationality.
研究人员发现，无论是年龄等人口统计因素，还是长期失业率等环境因素，与文化价值观的相关性都高于国籍。
Occupation and socio-economic status were the most strongly correlated, suggesting that our values are more economically driven than we usually give them credit for.
职业和社会经济地位的相关性最强，这表明我们的价值观比我们通常认为的更受经济驱动。
The evidence implies that people with similar jobs and incomes are more culturally alike, regardless of where they live.
这些证据意味着，职业和收入相近的人，无论住在哪里，在文化上都更为相似。
Vas Taras, the lead author of the study, puts it this way: “Tell me how much you make and I will make a pretty accurate prediction about your cultural values.
该研究的第一作者瓦斯·塔拉斯是这样说的：“告诉我你挣多少钱，我就会对你的文化价值观做出相当准确的预测。
Tell me what your nationality is and I probably will make a wrong prediction.”
告诉我你的国籍是什么，我很可能会做出错误的预测。”
Taras says our erroneous belief that countries are cultures has caused businesses to teach their employees useless or even harmful ways of interacting with their international peers.
塔拉斯说，我们以为国家就是文化，这种错误的看法已经导致企业教员工用一些无用甚至有害的方式与国际同行打交道。
Chinese and American lawyers might be trained to interact based on the assumption that the Chinese person is less individualistic, even though their similar socio-economic situations make it probable they are actually quite alike in that regard.
中国律师和美国律师在培训中可能会被教导，要基于中方个人主义倾向更弱这一假设来彼此打交道，尽管双方相近的社会经济状况使他们在这方面实际上很可能相当相似。
The country, as the unit of authority, is often a convenient way of generalizing about a population.
国家作为行使权力的单位，常常是笼统描述某一人群的便捷方式。
However, our focus on countries can mask broad variations within them.
然而，我们对国家的关注可能会掩盖各国内部的巨大差异。
In the majority of cases we would be better off identifying people by the factors that constrain their lives, like income, rather than by the lines surrounding them on a map.
在大多数情况下，我们最好依据收入等制约人们生活的因素来界定人们的身份，而不是依据地图上圈住他们的那些线条。